# Manas Ranjan Panigrahy (1) Featured

Data analyst, Data Warehousing, Data Architecture, Data Modeling, ETL Development, Business Intelligence, PL/SQL, SQL, Oracle, Tableau, SQL Plus, Toad, SQL Developer, SQL Loader, Teradata, Informatica Power Centre, Buisness analyst, BA



Current Designation: Software Developer -Database Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: DXC Technology Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Database Development, Data Warehousing, Data Architecture, Data Modeling, ETL

Development, Business Intelligence, PL/SQL, SQL, Oracle, Tableau, SQL Plus, Toad, SQL Developer, SQL

Loader, Teradata, Informatica Power Centre, Data Analytics, Analyst

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

## **Summary**

I am Having 6 Years of Experience in Development, Support and Maintenance. I was working as a consultant, Business analyst, Data analyst. As I Have worked on many technologies like Informatica, Tableau, Adobe analytics, Adhoc analysis, Oracle SQL/Plsql, Teradata SQLA and Vertica DB.

## Work Experience

**DXC Technology** as Software Developer -Database Sep 2018 to Till Date

Client: AT&T & OneAmerica

Title: Telecom eSales & services (At&T) & Product Insurance(One America)

Duration: Sep 2018 - Mar 2019 (AT&T) Duration: Apr 2019 to Present (OneAmerica)

Role: Software developer

Software: Informatica , Tableau, Sql, Plsql , Oracle 11g,

Responsibilities

Creating reports to analyze the market about sales and services.

Work with the latest data visualization techniques and technologies, evaluate new technologies, and innovate on new approaches to develop the best solutions and self-service analytics capabilities.

Work with Agile teams through all phases of the development life cycle, including helping to manage and report on the project's progress ETL Design, tests and debugs software according to as per standards, policies and procedures.

Developed and created Mapping, Maplets, workflows, Sessions and data pipelines using informatica.

Design all program specifications and perform required tests in same.

Prepare codes for all modules according to require specification and client requirements and prepare all required test plans.

Monitor all production issues and inquiries and provide efficient resolution for same.

Evaluate all functional requirements and map documents and perform troubleshoot on all development processes.

Documents all technical specifications and associate project deliverables.

Design all test cases to provide support to all systems and perform unit tests.

Worked on Attribute configuration.

Involved with ETL team for other teams such as Reporting, Testing, QA and Project Management for updates on Project Status and issues.

As a developer worked on Requirement gathering and requirement Analysis, Create PowerCenter Code creation, Code migration to the production, Conducted peer reviews.

Involved as a team member on Datamart work and Datawarehouse works.

#### Ark Cyber Solutions as Software Developer

Jun 2014 to Jul 2018

Project 1:

1/22/2021

Client: Tcs Tools: ETL, Toad, SQL Developer, SQL Loader. Jira

Title: Purchasing & sales system & Retail Banking Modules: Sales order, Product master

Duration: Aug 2016 - July 2018.( Retail Banking) Role: Software Developer

Duration: Oct 2014 - Apr 2016(Purchasing & sales system) Software: Oracle 11g, Windows

Project 1: Project Description: -

P&S Application is used to provide a centralized system to maintain all the point of sales and transactions being performed like Sales order, Challan, Product details. Primary users of this application are to implement and maintain for any retail business type of data handled by the application.

Project 2: Project Description: -

CBS Software for solving financial applications of a customer in banking environment in order to nurture the needs of an end banking user by providing various ways to perform banking tasks.

**RESPONSIBILITIES:-**

Effective and positive team player known for contributing effective creative solutions as well as technical ability. Knowledge on SQL/PL-SQL programming in Oracle 10g. Created solutions for data visualization to enhance business processes, worked with developers,

creating tableau dashboard reports, creating BI reports and visualizations, and participating in feedback sessions to improve systems.

Integrate Tableau with other platforms to create a modern, enjoyable, and effective user experience.

Generate ad-hoc user reports and clarify business user queries. Generate weekly/monthly management reports, metric reporting and issue tracking.

Performed ad-hoc analytics, reporting dashboard development, analytics tools development and developing foundational datasets for use in meaningful analytics.

Maintaining responsibility for developed dashboards and configure a server hosting environment to ensure consistent availability and performance across the enterprise when necessary. Exposure to

Quality conscious, Good Team player, Hardworking and enthusiastic in learning new things with target-oriented approach following timelines. Good ability to quickly grasp new concepts and technologies possessing problem-solving skills as well as hard working and above all a good team player.

Good communication skills in written and verbal.

#### Education

#### UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Kuvempu University, Bhubaneswar in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Gniit

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
PLSQL		2018	5 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
SQL PLUS,Toad,Sql developer.		2018	4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
WINDOWS,UNIX				
Oracle 11g, Windows	11g,12c	2019	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL Loader.		2018	4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	
TABLEAU	10.5.1	2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Adobe Analytics		2019	1 Year(s)	
Informatica		2019	5 Year(s)	
SQL		2019	4 Year(s)	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			
Oriya	Expert			
Telugu	Beginner			

## **Projects**

Project Title: Insurance Project

Client: One America

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2019 - Jan 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 20

Project Details: Working with Oracle SQL & Plsql and Etl Tool Like Informatica.

Project Title: Telecommunications Services

Client: AT&T

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 6 Role: Other

Skill Used: Tableau, Adobe analytics, Teradata, Vertica Database, Oracle SQL developer.

Role Description: Supporting the existing reports and developed new reports, Using Database querying and pulling the data. Project Details: Working as a Database developer and working with data visualization using tools like Tableau and Adobe

analytics.

Project Title: Purchasing & sales system

Client: TCS

Nature of Employment: Contractual Duration: Aug 2016 - Apr 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Skill Used: Oracle 11g, Windows

Role Description: Analysis, Design and development of PLSQL Program units such as Procedures, Functions, Triggers,

Packages using Advance PLSQL programming, Cursors and variables.

Project Details: P&S Application is used to provide a centralized system to maintain all the point of sales and transactions being performed like Sales order, Challan, Product details Primary users of this application are to implement and maintain for any retail business. Type of data handled by the application are position and transaction data for cash, deposits, sales orders, product master, general ledger. These functionalities are being hosted as an independent application in order to meet the Business requirements of Retail Business.

Project Title: Retail Banking

Client: TCS

Nature of Employment: Contractual Duration: Oct 2014 - Apr 2016

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Skill Used: Oracle 11g, Windows,unix

Role Description: Worked as Sql/PLSQL Developer in this project.

Written complex SQL Queries using Joins, Sub queries to retrieve data from the database.

Written a Trigger to generate Serial numbers while inserting records.

Project Details: CBS Software for solving financial applications of a customer in banking environment in order to nurture the needs of an end banking user by providing various ways to perform banking tasks. CBS processes daily banking transactions, and posts updates to accounts and financial accounts. It has Customer Details, Accounts, Deposit, Withdrawal modules with Bank branch details and Employee Information. This system also generates different reports like Statement of Account, Daily Transactions etc.

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time